Guide to the UE Local 610 Records, 1937-1990 UE.16.610
ULS Archives & Special Collections
- Subject Files, 1943-1987; 16.610.9.
  - Wage Scales: Trade and Craft - Switch, 1967-1972 (Box 27, Folder 28)
  - Westinghouse Airbrake Company: Parts Distribution, 1984 (Box 27, Folder 29)
  - Westinghouse Airbrake Office and Technical Unit: General, 1964-1974 (Box 27, Folder 30)
  - Westinghouse Airbrake Office and Technical Unit: Grievances, 1980-1981 (Box 27, Folder 31)
  - Wilmerding Diamond Jubilee, 1965 (Box 27, Folder 32)
  - Women's Labor Law, 1965-1970 (Box 27, Folder 33)
- Taft-Hartley Act, 1949-1959; 16.610.10.
  This series includes information on the Goldwater-Rhodes Bill and press clippings on the company and committee investigations into communist activities. This series also includes Local 610 noncommunist affidavit forms from 1954 to 1960 and the UE manual on Taft-Hartley procedures.
  - Taft-Hartley Compliance: Company Business, Press Clippings, 1953-1959 (Box 28, Folder 1)
  - Taft-Hartley Compliance: Goldwater-Rhodes Bill, 1953-1956 (Box 28, Folder 2)
  - Taft-Hartley Compliance: House Un-American Activities Committee Invasion of Civil Liberties, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 3)
  - Taft-Hartley Compliance: Senator Butler Hearings: Press Clippings, 1953 (Box 28, Folder 4)
  - Taft-Hartley Compliance, 1949-1958 (Box 28, Folder 05-08)
  - Taft-Hartley Compliance: Walter Committee, Press Clippings, 1959 (Box 28, Folder 9)
  - Taft-Hartley Compliance: UE Manual, 1951 (Box 28, Folder 10)
- 1981-1982 Strike, 16.610.11.
  The bulk of this series consists of newspaper articles and strike bulletins that document the progress of the strike. Additional files pertain to an injunction filed by the company to stop the strike and the arbitration on strike-related violence and vandalism.
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Arbitration, Strike Misconduct (Box 28, Folder 11-12)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Contract Information (Box 28, Folder 13)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Correspondence (Box 28, Folder 14)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Court Settlements (Box 28, Folder 15)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Discharged Employees (Box 28, Folder 16)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Dues Reimbursements, 1982-1983 (Box 28, Folder 17)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Injunction Case (Box 28, Folder 18-19)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Leaflets (Box 28, Folder 20)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Loans from the Union, 1982-1983 (Box 28, Folder 21)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Newspaper Articles (Box 28, Folder 22-23)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Organizing (Box 28, Folder 24)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Payment of Medical Bills, 1984 (Box 28, Folder 25)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Press Releases (Box 28, Folder 26)
  - 1981-1982 Strike: Bulletins (Box 28, Folder 27)
- Coalition to Save, 1984-1990; 16.610.12.
  This series contains information on the general campaign to save the Swissvale and Wilmerding plants from closing and the formation of the "Coalition to Save the Brake and Switch" organization. Extensive correspondence and newspaper articles document the actions taken to save the plants. The miscellaneous files include press statements, correspondence, arbitrations and collected information. More specific files exist for the Coalition to Save organization and include bylaws, meeting minutes, and financial and legal information. The PACE business retention study files contain an evaluation of the financial feasibility of maintaining operations at Wilmerding and Swissvale. The Steel Valley Authority files focus on the organizations efforts to keep the plants in operation. In addition to subject files, this series also contains a large quantity of cards written to the chairman of American Standard to stop the removal of work from Wilmerding/Swissvale to Canada and Southern United States.
  - American Standard Stockholders Resolution, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 1)
  - Card Campaign, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 2)
  - Coalition to Save the Brake and Switch: Bylaws and Minutes, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 3)
  - Coalition to Save the Brake and Switch: Correspondence, 1984-1987 (Box 29, Folder 4)
  - Coalition to Save the Brake and Switch: Financial, 1986-1990 (Box 29, Folder 5)
  - Coalition to Save the Brake and Switch: Legal, 1986-1988 (Box 29, Folder 6)
  - Correspondence: General, 1985-1986 (Box 29, Folder 07-08)
  - Correspondence: Switch Division, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 9)
  - Correspondence: Engineering Department Move, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 10)
  - Equipment Moves: Switch, 1986 (Box 29, Folder 11)
  - Information on the Movement of Work, 1985 (Box 29, Folder 12)
  - Leaflets, undated (Box 30, Folder 1)
  - List of Residents in Swissvale and Wilmerding, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 2)
  - Miscellaneous, 1984-1987 (Box 30, Folder 03-04)
  - Newspaper Articles, 1984-1986 (Box 30, Folder 05-08)
  - PACE Business Retention Study, 1985-1986 (Box 30, Folder 09-12)
  - Political Campaign, 1985-1986 (Box 30, Folder 13)
  - Proposal for New Transit Manufacturing, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 14)
  - Publications and Press Releases, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 15)
  - Publicity, 1985-1986 (Box 30, Folder 16)
  - Related Campaigns, N.D. (Box 30, Folder 17)
  - Sale of Swissvale Property, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 18)
  - Section 43: General, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 19)
  - Section 43: Grievances, 1984-1986 (Box 30, Folder 20)
  - Section 43: Outsourcing of Work, 1984 (Box 30, Folder 21)
  - Section 43: Petitions, undated (Box 30, Folder 22)
  - Severance Pay, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 23)
  - Shutdown Notices - Switch Division, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 24)
  - Shutdown Press Clippings - Switch Division, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 25)
  - Shutdown Threat - Airbrake, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 26)
  - Social Economic Impact of Plant Closings, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 27)
  - Steel Valley Authority, 1985-1986 (Box 30, Folder 28-30)
  - Switch P.E.A.R., 1985 (Box 30, Folder 31)
  - Union Questions and Company Response to Movement of Switch Division Work, 1985 (Box 30, Folder 32)
  - Voluntary Terminations, 1986 (Box 30, Folder 33)
- Trade Adjustment Act (TRA) and Severance Pay, 1983-1990; 16.610.13.
  These files contain information on Local 610's efforts to acquire severance pay and Trade Adjustment Act benefits for employees terminated from the Swissvale plant in 1986. The severance pay files include arbitrations, employee lists, correspondence, and other general information on the topic. The TRA files include program information, petitions for the release of confidential company information, eligibility of Local 610 workers, and the union's brief before the labor department for TRA assistance.
  - National Labor Relations Board Failure to Provide Information, 1986 (Box 31, Folder 1)
  - Questionnaire for Terminated Workers Severance Pay, 1989 (Box 31, Folder 2)
  - Appeals Case for Clarification on Arbitration, 1987-89 (Box 31, Folder 3)
  - Severance Pay Arbitrations: Airbrake Division, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 4)
  - Severance Pay Arbitrator Profiles, 1986-1987 (Box 31, Folder 5)
  - Severance Pay Arbitrations: Brief, 1986 (Box 31, Folder 6)
  - Severance Pay Arbitrations: General, 1984-1987 (Box 31, Folder 7)
  - Severance Pay Arbitrations: Settlement, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 8)
  - Severance Pay Arbitrations: Union Switch and Signal Division, 1984-1988 (Box 31, Folder 09-11)
  - Severance Pay: Correspondence, 1985-1986 (Box 31, Folder 12)
  - Severance Pay: Employee Lists, 1983-1990 (Box 31, Folder 13)
  - Severance Pay: Information on the Amounts Due, 1986-1989 (Box 31, Folder 14)
  - Severance Pay: Recipients, 1986-1987 (Box 31, Folder 15)
  - Severance Pay: Settlement - Employee Lists, 1989-1990 (Box 31, Folder 16)
  - Steel Valley Authority: Court Case, 1986 (Box 31, Folder 17)
  - Terminated Workers: Addresses, 1985-1989 (Box 31, Folder 18)
  - Terminations: Correspondence with Switch Manager, 1982-1986 (Box 31, Folder 19)
  - Trade Adjustment Act: Claimants, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 20)
  - Trade Adjustment Act: Confidential Company Material, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 21)
  - Trade Adjustment Act: Eligibility of Switch Employees, 1985-1987 (Box 31, Folder 22)
  - Trade Adjustment Act: General Program Information, 1986-1990 (Box 31, Folder 23)
  - Trade Adjustment Act: Plaintiff's Brief, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 24)
  - Trade Adjustment Act: Petition for Release of Confidential Information, 1987 (Box 31, Folder 25)
  - Trade Adjustment Act: Support of Plaintiff Request, 1988 (Box 31, Folder 26)
  - Trade Adjustment Act: Third Attempt, 1990 (Box 31, Folder 27)
- Membership Cards, 1937-1984; 16.610.14.
  Cards are arranged alphabetically by last name of the union member.
  - Airbrake Division Employees A-E (Box 32)
  - Airbrake Division Employees F-Mc (Box 33)
  - Airbrake Division Employees M-R (Box 34)
  - Airbrake Division Employees S-Z (Box 35)
  - Union Switch and Signal Division Employees A-Z, Later Additions of Membership Cards (Box 36)
- Job Descriptions and Rate Ranges, 1940-1981; 16.610.15.
  This series contains job descriptions from the Westinghouse Airbrake Company (WABCO) that date from 1943 to 1983. These descriptions were used for the salary negotiations. Also included are rate/wage ranges from WABCO that date from 1940 to 1980 and show the graduations of pay for each position depending on rank.
  - Job Descriptions: General, 1943-1983 (Box 37, Folder 01-04)
  - Job Descriptions: Airbrake, 1969-1975 (Box 37, Folder 05-06)
  - Job Descriptions: Engineering Section - Switch, 1964-1965 (Box 37, Folder 7)
  - Job Descriptions: Finance and Control - Switch, 1964-1965 (Box 37, Folder 8)
  - Job Descriptions: Hourly Employees - Switch, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 09-10)
  - Job Descriptions: Manufacturing, 1960s (Box 37, Folder 11)
  - Job Descriptions: Marketing Section, 1956-1965 (Box 37, Folder 12)
  - Job Descriptions: Salary, 1979-1980 (Box 37, Folder 13)
  - Job Descriptions: Trade and Craft, 1975-1977 (Box 37, Folder 14)
  - Rate Ranges: General, 1964 (Box 37, Folder 15)
  - Rate Ranges: Union Switch and Signal, 1963-1980 (Box 37, Folder 16-19)
  - Wage Rates: Airbrake Division, 1940-1946 (Box 37, Folder 20-21)
  - Wage Rates: Information, 1948-1949 (Box 37, Folder 22-23)
- Layoff, Recall, Seniority, Termination and Transfer Lists, 1959-1987; 16.610.16.
  This series contains internal memos and lists of individuals who faced layoff, recall, termination or transfer. These memoranda/lists generally contain employee name, check number, seniority, and date of activity (layoff, recall, termination, etc.). The termination files from April 1986 include the worker service record and document changes in worker occupation.
  - Discharges, 1978-1979 (Box 38, Folder 1)
  - Layoffs: Airbrake Division, 1982-1986 (Box 38, Folder 02-05)
  - Layoffs: Out of Seniority, 1984 (Box 38, Folder 6)
  - Layoffs: Union Switch and Signal Division, 1982-1986 (Box 38, Folder 07-09)
  - Layoffs: Voluntary, 1983-1984 (Box 38, Folder 10)
  - New and Recalled Members - Airbrake, 1980-1984 (Box 38, Folder 11)
  - Recalls: Airbrake Division, 1982-1985 (Box 38, Folder 12-13)
  - Recalls: Out of Seniority, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 14)
  - Recalls: Union Switch and Signal Division, 1959-1987 (Box 38, Folder 15-22)
  - Seniority Lists: Airbrake, 1985-1987 (Box 38, Folder 23)
  - Seniority Lists: Miscellaneous, 1980-1987 (Box 38, Folder 24-26)
  - Seniority Lists: Union Switch and Signal Division, 1983-1985 (Box 39, Folder 01-06)
  - Signed Agreements for Layoff and Recalls, 1961-1980 (Box 39, Folder 7)
  - Terminations: General, 1985-1987 (Box 39, Folder 8-10)
  - Terminations: Out of Seniority, 1986-1987 (Box 39, Folder 11)
  - Terminations: Union Switch and Signal Division, 1975-1981 (Box 39, Folder 12-13)
  - Transfers: Airbrake, 1981-1987 (Box 39, Folder 14-19)
  - Transfers: Union Switch and Signal Division, 1981 (Box 39, Folder 20)